RG 041:001, Board of Railroad Commissioners
Connecticut State Library
- Series 3. Railroad Papers, circa 1848-1911, bulk 1860-1911; 19.25 cubic feet; 1932-074
  - New Haven, Middletown & Willimantic R.R., 1869-1877 (Box 35, Folder 5-7)
  - New London Northern R.R., 1866-1891 (Box 35, Folder 8-9)
    The New London Northern R.R. papers in Boxes 35 and 36 include New London, Willimantic & Palmer R.R. and the Central Vermont Railway.
  - New London Northern R.R., 1892-1911 (Box 36, Folder 1-5)
  - New York & New England R.R., 1872-1879 (Box 36, Folder 6-8)
  - New York & New England R.R., 1880-1883 July (Box 37, Folder 1-8)
  - New York & New England R.R., 1883 August - 1887 June (Box 38, Folder 1-8)
  - New York & New England R.R., 1887 July - 1896 (Box 39, Folder 1-8)
  - New York & New England R.R., 1897-1905 (Box 40, Folder 1-8)
    The New York & New England R.R. papers in Boxes 39-42 include the reorganized New England Railroad, 1895-1911.
  - New York & New England R.R., 1906 April - 1909 May 6 (Box 41, Folder 1-8)
  - New York & New England R.R., 1909 May 12 - 1911 (Box 42, Folder 1-4)
  - New York & New Haven R.R., 1860 - 1867 August (Box 42, Folder 5-10)
  - New York & New Haven R.R., 1867 September - 1878 July (Box 43, Folder 1-10)
  - New York & New Haven R.R., 1878 August - 1885 (Box 44, Folder 1-10)
  - New York & New Haven R.R., 1886-1892 December 31 (Box 45, Folder 1-10)
  - New York & New Haven R.R., 1892 December 31 - 1893 November (Box 46, Folder 1-10)
  - New York & New Haven R.R., 1894-1898 June (Box 47, Folder 1-10)
  - New York & New Haven R.R., 1898 August - 1907 July (Box 48, Folder 1-10)
  - New York & New Haven R.R., 1907 September - 1911 (Box 49, Folder 1-4)
  - New York & New Haven R.R.: capital stock, 1889-1893 (Box 49, Folder 5-6)
  - New York, Providence & Boston R.R., 1867-1908 (Box 49, Folder 7-12)
  - Norwich & Worcester R.R., 1860-1905 (Box 50, Folder 1-10)
  - Norwich & Worcester R.R., 1906-1911 (Box 51, Folder 1-2)
  - Shepaug Railroad, 1871-1911 (Box 51, Folder 3-8)
  - Shore Line Railway, 1861-1874 (Box 51, Folder 9-10)
    The Shore Line Railway papers in Boxes 51-53 include New Haven & New London R.R., New London & Stonington R.R., Stonington & Providence R.R., and New Haven, New London & Stonington R.R.
  - Shore Line Railway, 1875-1892 May (Box 52, Folder 1-10)
  - Shore Line Railway, 1892 July - 1911 (Box 53, Folder 1-9)
  - South Manchester R.R., 1879-1910 (Box 53, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous railroads, 1902-1905 (Box 54, Folder 1)
    Includes Manufacturers R.R. (New Haven), Union Metallic Cartridge Co. Industrial R.R. (Bridgeport)
  - Danbury & State Line Railway (proposed), 1892-1893 (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - New York & Connecticut Railway (proposed), 1881 (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - New York & Connecticut Airline R.R. (proposed), 1881-1884 (Box 54, Folder 4-8)
  - New York & Connecticut Eastern R.R. (proposed), 1880 (Box 54, Folder 9)
  - New York, Bridgeport & Eastern Railway (proposed), 1890-1891 (Box 55, Folder 1-2)
  - Miscellaneous proposed railroads, 1887-1903 (Box 55, Folder 3)
    Includes Ridgefield and New York R.R., Westport and Redding R.R., Windsor Locks R.R.
  - Car couplers, 1878-1882 March (Box 55, Folder 4-9)
  - Car couplers, 1882 April - 1887 (Box 56, Folder 1-2)
  - Grade crossings, 1883-1891 (Box 56, Folder 3-8)
- Series 4. Hearings, 1875-1883, undated; .25 cubic feet; 1932-074
  - Front cover only for hearing on location of Connecticut Central R.R., circa 1875 May 14 (Box 56, Folder 9)
    Damage appraisals can be found in Connecticut Central R.R. papers in Series 3
  - Tariffville inquest, 1878 January 22 - February 5 (Box 56, Folder 9)
    Books 1-3
    Accident occurred January 15, 1878
  - Tariffville inquest, 1878 February 5-12, undated (Box 56, Folder 10)
    Book 4 and unnumbered book
    Accident occurred on January 15, 1878
  - New York & New England R.R., Naugatuck R.R., and Connecticut Western R.R. connections, 1878 December 18, 1879 June 6 (Box 56, Folder 10)
    Books 1 and 2
  - New York. & New England R.R., Naugatuck R.R., and Connecticut Western R.R. connections, 1879 June (Box 56, Folder 11)
  - Pomfret collision, 1882 November 15 (Box 56, Folder 11)
    Collision occurred on November 4, 1882
  - Miscellaneous matters, 1882 November (Box 56, Folder 11)
    Contains: Hearings at Willimantic, November 2, 1882; hearings at Hartford, November 8, 14, 15, 1882
  - Accident on Springfield Division at South Windsor; Accident at Union City, 1882 December (Box 56, Folder 12)
    Hearing for accident at South Windsor that occurred on December 11, 1882; the collision at Union City occurred on December 14, 1882
  - New York & Connecticut Airline R.R. right of way at Bridgeport, 1883 July 25 (Box 56, Folder 12)
  - Hartford Tunnel collision, 1883 July 24 (Box 56, Folder 12)
    Book 1
    New York & New England R.R. and N.Y., N.H. & H. R.R. trains collided just north of the tunnel on June 30, 1883
  - Hartford Tunnel collision, 1883 July 24 (Box 56, Folder 12)
    Book 2
  - Hartford Tunnel photographs, 2 photographs (Box 56, Folder 13)
  - Hartford Freight Branch collision, 1883 July 12, 17, 27 (Box 56, Folder 13)
    Collision occurred on June 7, 1883
  - Plainville collision, undated (Box 56, Folder 13)
    Collision occurred on July 9, 1883
- Series 5. Street Railway Papers, 1889-1911; 6.5 cubic feet; 1932-074
  - American Tube & Stamping Co., 1902 (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - Branford Lighting & Water Co., 1904 (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - Bridgeport & Danbury Electric Railway, 1911 (Box 57, Folder 3)
  - Bridgeport Traction Co., 1897-1899 (Box 57, Folder 4)
  - Bristol & Plainville Tramway, 1894-1907 (Box 57, Folder 5-6)
  - Central Railway & Electric Co. (New Britain), 1889-1899 (Box 57, Folder 7-9)
  - Cheshire Street Railway, 1901-1905 (Box 58, Folder 1-2)
  - Connecticut Railway & Lighting Co., 1901-1905 June 19 (Box 58, Folder 3-8)
  - Connecticut Railway & Lighting Co., 1905 June 30 - 1910 June (Box 59, Folder 1-8)
  - Danbury & Bethel Street Railway, 1898-1908 (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - Danbury & Golden's Bridge Street Railway, 1901 (Box 60, Folder 2)
  - Danielson & Norwich Street Railway, 1902 (Box 60, Folder 3)
  - East Hartford & Glastonbury Street Railway, 1905 (Box 60, Folder 4)
  - Enfield & Longmeadow Electric Railway, 1897-1898 (Box 60, Folder 5)
  - Fair Haven and Westville R.R., 1901-1903 (Box 60, Folder 6)
  - Farmington Street Railway, 1902 (Box 60, Folder 7)
  - Greenwich Tramway, 1901-1905 (Box 60, Folder 8)
  - Groton & Stonington Street Railway, 1904-1911 (Box 60, Folder 9)
  - Hartford & Springfield Street Railway, 1894-1901 November 19 (Box 60, Folder 10-12)
  - Hartford & Springfield Street Railway, 1902 January - 1910 (Box 61, Folder 1-8)
  - Hartford, Rockville & Manchester Tramway, 1894-1898 (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - Meriden Electric R.R., 1896-1904 (Box 62, Folder 2)
  - Meriden, Middletown & Guilford Electric Railway, 1909-1910 (Box 62, Folder 3)
  - Meriden, Southington & Compounce Tramway, 1899-1905 (Box 62, Folder 4)
  - Middletown Street Railway, 1903 (Box 62, Folder 5)
  - Montville Street Railway, 1903-1904 (Box 62, Folder 6)
  - Naugatuck Valley Street Railway, 1905-1907 (Box 62, Folder 7)
  - New London & East Lyme Street Railway, 1905 (Box 62, Folder 8)
  - New York, New Haven & Hartford, Consolidated Railway Co., 1904 - 1907 June 12 (Box 63, Folder 1-6)
  - New York, New Haven & Hartford, Street Railway Lines, 1907 June 19 - October (Box 63, Folder 7-9)
  - New York, New Haven & Hartford, Street Railway Lines, 1907 November - 1909 September (Box 64, Folder 1-8)
  - New York, New Haven & Hartford, Street Railway Lines, 1909 October - December (Box 65, Folder 1-2)
  - New York, New Haven & Hartford, Connecticut Company, 1910 February - 1911 June 7 (Box 65, Folder 3-9)
  - New York, New Haven & Hartford, Connecticut Company, 1911 June 10 - 1912 (Box 66, Folder 1-4)
  - Norwalk Tramway, 1899-1900 (Box 66, Folder 5)
  - Norwich & Westerly Street Railway, 1906 (Box 66, Folder 6)
  - Norwich Street Railway, 1897-1904 (Box 66, Folder 7)
  - People's Tramway (Putnum), 1899-1900 (Box 66, Folder 8)
  - Rockville, Broad Brook & East Windsor Street Railway, 1905 July 5 - 1910 (Box 66, Folder 9-11)
  - Shore Line Electric Railway, 1907-1911 (Box 67, Folder 1-8)
  - Somers & Enfield Street Railway, 1902-1903 (Box 67, Folder 9)
  - Stafford Springs Street Railway, 1902-1907 (Box 68, Folder 1-3)
  - Stamford Street R.R., 1902-1904 (Box 68, Folder 4)
  - Suffield Street Railway, 1901-1904 (Box 68, Folder 5-6)
  - Thomaston Tramway, 1905-1907 (Box 68, Folder 7)
  - Wallingford Tramway, 1903-1904 (Box 68, Folder 8)
  - Waterbury Traction Co., 1896 (Box 68, Folder 9)
  - Willimantic Traction Co., 1901-1904 (Box 69, Folder 1-2)
  - Windsor Locks & Rainbow Street Railway, 1904 (Box 69, Folder 3)
  - Winchester Ave. R.R. (New Haven), 1894-1904 (Box 69, Folder 4)
  - Worcester & Connecticut Eastern Railway, including Thompson Tramway, 1902-1903 (Box 69, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous street railways, 1894-1911 (Box 69, Folder 6)
    Includes: Hartford and West Hartford R.R., Norwich, Colchester and Hartford Traction Co., Providence and Danielson Railway, Steeplechase Island R.R. (Bridgeport), Torrington and Winchester Street Railway, West Shore Railway, Windsor Locks Traction Co., Suffield Street Railway.
  - Fenders, 1895-1896 (Box 69, Folder 7)
  - Vestibules, 1895-1909 (Box 69, Folder 8-10)
- Series 6. Asylum Street Bridge Commission, 1884-1892; .5 cubic feet; 1932-074
  - Records, 1884-1889 (Box 70, Folder 1-5)
  - Record book, 1884-1892; 1 volume (Box 70)
    Contents: Record of orders drawn, 1886-1892; minutes, 1884-1892
- Series 7. Miscellaneous Records, 1871-1909, undated; .25 cubic feet; 1932-074
  - Inspection notebooks, 1871-1881, 1909; 2 items (Box 71, Folder 1)
  - Leather pouch, undated; fragile (Box 71, Folder 2)
    Engraved "Board of Railroad Commissioners / State Capitol Hartford Conn."
  - Name and address book, undated (Box 71, Folder 3)
  - Unidentified index, undated (Box 71, Folder 4)
    Includes references to newspapers.
- Series 8. Scrapbooks, 1879-1909; 5 cubic feet (23 volumes); 1932-074
  - 1879 June 4 - 1880 March 31, 1 volume (Box 72)
  - 1880 April 1 - October 27, 1 volume (Box 72)
  - 1883 February 8 - June 16, 1 volume (Box 72)
  - 1883 November 21 - 1884 March 28, 1 volume (Box 72)
    Spine states start date as 1883 November 24
  - 1884 March 27 - 1885 February 20, 1 volume (Box 72)
  - 1885 February 20 - October 24, 1 volume (Box 73)
  - 1885 October 22 - 1886 May 15, 1 volume (Box 73)
  - 1886 May 4 - 1887 January 26, 1 volume (Box 73)
  - 1887 January 26 - May 18, 1 volume (Box 73)
  - 1887 September 14 - 1888 February 10, 1 volume (Box 73)
  - 1888 December 14 - 1889 April 25, 1 volume (Box 74)
  - 1889 April 24 - 1889 December 10, 1 volume (Box 74)
  - 1889 December 10 - 1890 October 16, 1 volume (Box 74)
  - 1890 September 8 - 1891 November 30, 1 volume (Box 74)
  - 1891 November 30 - 1892 November 22, 1 volume (Box 74)
  - 1892 November 22 - 1893 August 3, 1 volume (Box 75)
  - 1893 August 3 - 1894 August 31, 1 volume (Box 75)
  - 1894 August 31 - 1895 August 31, 1 volume (Box 75)
  - 1895 September 2 - 1897 February 12, 1 volume (Box 75)
  - 1897 February 10 - 1899 January 14, 1 volume (Box 76)
  - 1899 January 16 - 1901 January 17, 1 volume (Box 76)
  - 1900 December 1- 1902 June 14, 1 volume (Box 76)
  - 1904 November 2 - 1909 December 3, 1 volume (Box 76)
- Series 9. Accident Reports, 1893-1911; 3 cubic feet (19 volumes); 1932-074
  - Boston & New York Air Line R.R., 1893 October 18 - 1911 May 22; 1 volume (Box 77)
    N.Y., N.H. & Hartford R.R. Air Line, Northampton, Shore Line, and Midland Divisions. Reports mainly cover New Haven to Willimantic.
  - Danbury & Norwalk R.R., 1893 July 11 - 1911 July 24; 1 volume (Box 77)
    N.Y., N.H. & Hartford R.R. Danbury and Western Divisions. Reports mainly cover South Norwalk to Brookfield.
  - Hartford & Connecticut Valley R.R., 1893 October 17 - 1911 August 1; 1 volume (Box 77)
    N.Y., N.H. & Hartford R.R. Valley and Shore Line Divisions. Reports mainly cover Hartford to Saybrook.
  - Hartford & New Haven R.R., 1906 August 3 - 1911 August 2; 1 volume (Box 77)
    On spine: "NH & H"
    N.Y., N.H. & Hartford R.R. Midland, Hartford, and Shore Line Divisions. Reports mainly cover New Haven to Enfield, plus New Britain.
  - Housatonic R.R., 1910 January 15 - 1911 July 15; 1 volume (Box 77)
    N.Y., N.H. & Hartford R.R. Western Division. Reports mainly cover Hawleyville (Newtown) to Pittsfield, Mass.
  - Naugatuck R.R., 1908 September 10 - 1911 August 2; 1 volume (Box 77)
    N.Y., N.H. & Hartford R.R. Western Division. Reports mainly cover Devon (Milford) to Winsted.
  - New Canaan R.R., 1911 July 3; 1 volume (Box 78)
    There is only one document in this volume.
  - New Haven & Derby R.R., 1893 July 12 - 1911 June 24; 1 volume (Box 78)
    N.Y., N.H. & Hartford R.R. Berkshire, Naugatuck, and Western Divisions. Reports mainly cover New Haven to Ansonia, Derby Jct. to Botsford (Newtown).
  - New Haven & Northampton R.R., 1893 July 6 - 1911 July 14; 1 volume (Box 78)
    N.Y., N.H. & Hartford R.R. Northampton, Air Line, and Shore Line Divisions. Reports mainly cover New Haven to Granby; Farmington to New Hartford.
  - New London Northern R.R., 1893 August 21 - 1911 May 24; 1 volume (Box 78)
    Central Vermont Railway New London and Southern Divisions. Reports cover New London to Massachusetts.
  - New York & New England R.R., 1909 May 20 - 1911 February 23; 1 volume (Box 78)
    On spine: "NY&NE"
    N.Y., N,H. & H. R.R. Midland, Western, and Shore Line Divisions. Reports cover Thompson to Danbury.
  - New York & New England R.R., 1911 February 27 - 1911 August 1; 1 volume (Box 78)
    N.Y., N,H. & H. R.R. Midland and Western Divisions. Reports cover Thompson to Danbury.
  - New York & New Haven R.R., 1908 December 12 - 1911 July 26; 1 volume (Box 79)
    N.Y., N.H. & H. R.R. Shore Line and New York Divisions. Reports cover New Haven to Greenwich.
  - New York, Providence & Boston R.R., 1911 November 7 - July 22; 1 volume (Box 79)
    N.Y., N.H. & H. R.R. Worcester, Shore Line, and Providence Divisions. Reports mainly cover New London to Stonington.
  - Norwich & Worcester R.R., 1893 July 3 - 1911 August 2; 1 volume (Box 79)
    New York & New England R.R.; New England R.R.; N.Y. N.H. & H. R.R Shore Line and Midland Divisions; Central Vermont Railway. Reports mainly cover Groton to Thompson.
  - Philadelphia, Reading & New England R.R., 1909 June 21 - 1911 August 7; 1 volume (Box 79)
    On spine: "PR&NE"
    Central New England Railway. Reports cover Hartford to Suffield and to Salisbury.
  - Shepaug R.R., 1903 May 12 - 1911 July 10; 1 volume (Box 79)
    N.Y., N.H. & H. R.R. Berkshire, Naugatuck, and Western Divisions. Reports cover Hawleyville (Newtown) to Litchfield.
  - Shore Line Railway, 1904 September 6 - 1911 June 13; 1 volume (Box 79)
    N.Y., N.H. & H. R.R. Shore Line Division. Reports cover New Haven to Midway (Groton).
- Series 10. Docket Maps, 1870-1912; 13 cubic feet; 1986-025
  Numbered 1-737
  Listing available at History & Genealogy Reference desk. These items are identified on the listing with the code "RRC". The listing also include maps, charts, and blueprints submitted post-1911 to the Public Utilities Commission as well as those removed from Series 3 and 5 during processing.
- Series 11. Card Index Files, 5.5 cubic feet; 1932-074
  - Subseries 11.1. Index to Board actions
    Compiled from the indexes in Series 1, Record Books up to volume 41.
    - Accident - Connecticut Western R.R. (Box 80)
    - Crossing grade - Gowdy (Box 81)
    - Grade Crossings - Naugatuck R.R. Inspection (Box 82)
    - Naugatuck R.R., Order - NYNH&H R.R. Petition (Box 83)
    - NYNH&H R.R. Petition - Permit (Box 84)
    - Perry - Petition (Box 85)
    - Petition - Yudkin; plus miscellaneous matters (Box 86)
  - Subseries 11.2. Index to accidents
    Compiled from the indexes in Series 1, Record Books up to volume 41, these cards list accident victims, 1853-1893, by surname with incident location, reporting railroad, and incident report date.
    The information on these cards was used to create "Index to Accidents Reported to the Railroad Commissioners, 1858-1893" by Connecticut State Library staff in 1998. This index contains the 6,319 surnames in the card file with a large number listed under "U" for unknown. A copy of this index is available at the History & Genealogy reference desk.
    - Abel - Cavendish (Box 87)
    - Cestaro - Day (Box 88)
    - Deal - Hopson (Box 89)
    - Horan - Mazzucco (Box 90)
    - McAllister - Penfield (Box 91)
    - Percival - Sturgis (Box 92)
    - Sullivan - Zink (Box 93)
  - Subseries 11.3. Index to plans
    Index includes plans submitted to the Board of Railroad Commissioners (RRC) and the Public Utilities Commission (PUC).
    A listing of plans by town is available at the History & Genealogy reference desk.
    - RRC, street railway plans, by company (Box 94)
    - RRC, steam railroad plans, by company (Box 94)
    - PUC, all plans, by company, A - NYNH&H Co., Plan 720 (Box 95)
    - PUC, all plans, by company, NYNH&H Co., Plan 722 - end (Box 96)
    - RRC, street railway plans, by town and village (Box 96)
    - RRC, steam railroad plans, by town and village, A - H (Box 96)
    - RRC, steam railroad plans, by town and village, K - W (Box 97)
    - PUC, all plans, by town and village, A - New Hartford (Box 97)
    - PUC, all plans, by town and village, New Haven - end (Box 98)
    - RRC, street railway plans, by street name/miscellaneous location (Box 98)
    - RRC, steam railroad plans, by street name/miscellaneous location (Box 99)
    - PUC, all plans, by street name/miscellaneous location, A - Church St. (Box 99)
    - PUC, all plans, by street name/miscellaneous location, Conduit - end; plus Subject File and miscellaneous plans (Box 100)
- Series 12. Maps, 1881-1905; 1983-028
  - Maps of the railroads of Connecticut to accompany the report of the Railroad Commissioners, 1881, 1888-1890, 1893-1905; 17 items (Box map case)
    Copies of, are in StLib Spec Coll Maps, and is in StLib History Ref Map Case.